If you think about most of the native apps that you use,
如果你去看看使用过的原生应用
mostly all of them are really just lists.
就会发现基本上都是一堆列表信息
Spotify, Facebook, all of the most popular apps,
Spotify、Facebook 和所有其他的热门应用
are just these huge lists of data that are constantly changing.
都只是显示一些不断变化的庞大列表数据
So, what we're going to do in this video is talk about how we
在本视频中 我们将介绍
can have performant lists inside of react-native.
如何在 react-native 中添加能正常运行的列表
So, what I have here is this reviews.js file.
这是一个 reviews.js 文件
It's just an array with a bunch of different items in it.
其实就是一个包含各组不同项目的数组
And then, we have a getReviews function which just exports,
然后是一个 getReviews 函数
or basically returns, that array.
用来返回上面的数组
So, inside of our app,
转到 App.js 文件
what we've done is we've imported getReviews,
我们导入了 getReviews
and then I have this review component here that accepts a name,
并在这里添加了 Review 组件
some text, and an avatar,
它会接收名称、文本和头像
and then basically just displays that information to the View.
并向 View 显示这些信息
So, what we're going to do is walk through the different ways that we can
我们将逐步介绍在应用中
display all of these reviews in our app.
显示所有这些评价的不同方式
So, the first way, and the most obvious way,
首先 也是最明显的方式是
is to do something like this.
输入以下内容
Where we come in here, and we say,
转到这里
we've used that map, just as we would do on the web.
输入 reviews.map 就像在网络平台上一样
So, we get a name, a text,
获得 name、text
and an avatar, and then,
和 avatar
we go ahead and just render our review component,
然后渲染 Review 组件
passing it a key which is just going to be, let's say, the name,
传入 key 该 key 将为 name
then we can pass it the name,
然后传入 name
text, and also the avatar.
text 和 avatar
So, this works, kind of.
看起来似乎可行
Let's go ahead and look at our apps.
看看应用效果
So, you'll notice here everything looks fine,
你会发现一切看起来正常
but if we go to scroll,
但是如果滚动的话
you notice we can't scroll because the view is confined to the area on the screen.
却发现无法滚动 因为视图被限定在这么大的屏幕空间内
So, an easy fix we can do for this,
解决方法很简单
is instead of using View,
我们不再使用 View
what we can do is we can wrap our list inside of this scroll view component.
而是将列表封装在这个 ScrollView 组件中
So, now what we're saying is everything inside of
现在
here is going to be a list and it should be able to scroll.
这里面的一切都是列表 并且应该能够滚动
So, now, inside of our app,
现在 在我们的应用中
notice here that we can scroll,
我们能够滚动了
but the problem with ScrollView is that it's not really that performant.
但是 ScrollView 并不是那么强大 也存在问题
What we're doing is we're rendering
我们现在的做法是
each item in this list regardless if the user can see it or not.
渲染该列表中的每一项 无论用户是否能看到这些项
So, when we're at the top of this view,
当我们位于该视图的顶部时
we're still rendering all of these reviews down here.
依然在渲染下面的评价
It would be nice and a little bit more performant,
比较高效的做法是
if instead of rendering all of the items we
我们不用渲染所有项目
just go ahead and render the items that the user can currently see.
而是只渲染用户当前能看到的项目
And that is where this FlatList component is going to come into play.
这时候 这个 FlatList 组件就派上用场了
It's going to do exactly that,
它完全能实现刚才提到的渲染效果
just render the items that the user can currently see.
只渲染用户当前查看的项目
So, let's change our scroll view back to just a regular view,
将 ScrollView 重新改为普通的 View
and then inside of our view,
然后在 View 里面
what we can do is we can render our FlatList component,
渲染 FlatList 组件
and we're going to pass it two different things.
将传入两项不同的内容
It needs some data,
需要一些数据
which we have here as reviews,
设为 reviews
and it also needs
还需要 renderItem
renderItem which is going to be responsible for rendering the actual items.
它负责渲染实际的项目
So, what we'll do here, is we will create a renderItem method,
在这里创建一个 renderItem 方法
and then, I'm just going to copy all of this and delete that.
复制所有这些内容并删掉这些内容
So, now let's go ahead and create renderItem.
现在开始创建 renderItem
So, what renderItem is going to receive,
renderItem 将接收一个对象
is an object with the actual item itself being the thing that we're mapping over.
并且实际项目本身是要映射的内容
So, each item is going to be a specific review,
每个 item 都将是具体的 Review
and then what we want to do,
然后我们将
is we want to go ahead and render a review passing in the item.
渲染 Review 并传入该 item
So, now, what we'll see is everything should look the exact same,
现在再看看应用效果 一切应该看起来没变化
and it really scrolls the same,
滚动效果还是一样的
but when you're using this app on
但是当你在实际手机上运行该应用
an actual phone and you're scrolling through this long list,
并滚动查看这么长的列表
you're going to notice a huge performance gain because again, with FlatList,
会发现效果好多了 因为我们使用的是 FlatList
instead of rendering the entire list,
我们只是渲染用户当前看到的具体项目
is we're just rendering the specific items that the user can currently see.
而不是整个列表